Joel Aheybor PMP

Project Manager / Governance, Risk and Compliance Enthusiast

Phone Number +2347038841785
Email Aheyborjoel@gmail.com
Address Nigeria, Lagos, 100244
Linkedin www.linkedin.com/in/aheybor/

I am an experienced PMP with 4+ years of experience managing EdTech projects worth over \$30,000 that won the Nigeria Communication Commission's innovation prize. With expert stakeholder engagement and product development skills has developed 12+ STEM products generating over \$12,000 recurring per annum. I am seeking to lead businesses in project management, product development, governance, risk and compliance to reduce the risk of project failure and deliver value to stakeholders.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Product Manager

Enhanced STEM Solution, Brainiacs STEM & Robotics, Lagos

Feb 2023 - Present

- Effectively managed the KPI scorecard of 12 core staff in 3 states, resulting in a 10% increase in sales, a 5% decrease in customer churn, and a 15% improvement in employee satisfaction.
- Grew client base by 20% by sharing monthly analysis and insights with stakeholders, which highlighted new market opportunities and helped to improve customer satisfaction.

Associate Member

Professional Development Team, Project Management Institute, Nigeria

Jan 2022 - Present

- Influenced teams of up to 5 people to gain 100% of their buy-in and support towards using Jira as a project management tool. Overcome challenges such as resistance to change and lack of familiarity with the tool by providing clear and concise training, offering ongoing support, and demonstrating the benefits of using Jira.
- Led the sourcing and onboarding of speakers for the team's monthly webinar, which has over 80 attendees. Secured speakers from leading consulting organizations such as Afrissance and CFO.NG to speak on topics such as change project management, business acumen, and earned value management. The webinars have been well-received by the team and have helped them to stay up-to-date on the latest trends in project management.

Project Development Manager

Brainiacs STEM & Robotics, Lagos

Dec 2020 - Feb 2023

- Implemented a hybrid project methodology to produce three STEM products 30% faster than planned and 24% under budget.
- Created a working agreement document and negotiated with eight contractors and ten vendors to save 25% on project costs.
- Successfully planned, executed, and launched 16 Educational Products, two kits, and two STEAM Manuals that won the Nigeria Communication Communications Innovation Award.

Product Manager

Letslearn NG, Brainiacs STEM & Robotics, Lagos

Aug 2020 - Dec 2020

• Secured a \$2,000 B2C partnership with Standard Bearers Schools by gathering requirements, writing a proposal, and developing a strategic plan. The partnership resulted in a 20% increase in sales for my company.

Field Support Specialist/Project Lead

Brainiacs STEM & Robotics, Lagos

Sep 2019 - Aug 2020

- Led a team of 10 to complete an Oracle Company coding and robotics camp project, earning me a promotion.
- Successfully executed a virtual three-week camp project with 100+ learners and 12+ instructors across three
 countries as camp director.

• Delivered a training titled "Increasing ROI Using Collaborative Tools & Effective Web Analytics" that resulted in a 35% increase in team collaboration.

Technical Team Lead

Care For Seven Foundation (Bright Hands Project), UK

Jul - Aug 2019

- Collaborated with a team of 8 and lead the solar training facilitation of 38 learners aged 9 17 with a success rate
 of 100%.
- Managed the development of impact reports for stakeholders and sponsors at the University of Rochester, working
 closely with organizers to ensure that reports were accurate, timely, and user-friendly.

Student Project Coordinator

Government Day Secondary School, Jigawa

May 2018 - Mar 2019

- Worked in a team of 5 to develop and execute a program of educational speeches and debates that increased students' academic performance by 35%.
- Wrote a proposal for a group community development project that trained 30 students in leadership, communication, and project management skills.

Assistant Technologist/Project Lead

Alberg Geophysical Limited, Edo

Dec 2017 - Apr 2018

- Led a team of 3 engineers in the development of a new inverter prototype.
- Simplified inverter experimental circuitry and assembled the prototype within 4 months.
- · Trained and mentored team members in layout, assembly procedures, and problem-solving through sketches

IT Researcher Intern

Campus 196 Online Ltd, Edo

Feb - Nov 2015

- Trained and mentored team members in layout, assembly procedures, and problem-solving through sketches
 Worked with the marketing team to redesign the company's website, which resulted in a 25% increase in website
 traffic and a 15% increase in leads generated.
- Developed a user-friendly help centre that included articles, videos, and FAQs covering all aspects of the company's products and services.

EDUCATION

BSc In Computer Science, Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Nigeria

2020 - 2023

- 4.72/5.00 CGPA
- · Co-published two academic papers on blockchain usability and automated systems with my supervisor
- Pursed a passion for project management and Computer Networks/Communication coursework

HND In Physics and Electronics, Auchi Federal Polytechnic, Nigeria

2015 - 2017

- 4.94/5.00 CGPA
- Won three school awards worth over \$800 as the overall best-graduating student

ADDITIONAL INFORMATIONN

Skills: Negotiation | Budget Management | Project Scheduling | Strategic Planning and Analysis | Risk Management | Product Development | Predictive, Agile and Hybrid Methodologies | Proficient with Jira, Asana, MS Project and Office | Requirement Gathering | Exceptional Verbal and Written Communication | Stakeholder Engagement

Certification: Project Management Professional (PMP)

Awards: Most outstanding 2022 PMI Nigeria volunteers | 2021 Nigeria Communication Commission ICT Innovation Competition 2nd Prize

Conferences: 2022 PMI Africa Conference | 2022 PMI Nigeria Expo and Conference